I've been playing TED for nearly a decade,
انا أعزف الموسيقى لمؤتمرات " تيد " منذ نحو عقد من الزمن
and I've very rarely played
وكنت قليلا ما اعزف
any new songs of my own.
أغاني جيدة لنفسي
And that was largely because there weren't any.
وكان سبب هذا انني لا املك تلك الاغاني- الجيدة -ربما
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So I've been busy with a couple of projects,
لذا كنت مشغولا بمشروعين
and one of them was this:
وواحد منهم كان هذا ..
The Nutmeg.
" ذا نت ميج "
A 1930s ship's lifeboat,
وهي سفينة إنقاذ منذ 1930
which I've been restoring in the garden
والتي كنت احتفظ بها في حديقتي
of my beach house in England.
في منزلي الشاطئي في انجلترا
And, so now,
وهكذا ..
when the polar ice caps melt,
وعندما يذوب القطب الشمالي
my recording studio will rise up like an ark,
سوف اطوف انا ومعداتي الصوتية كسفينة نوح
and I'll float off into the drowned world
وسوف اطوف واغرق في العالم
like a character from a J.G. Ballard novel.
مثل شخصية رواية " جي - بالارد "
During the day,
واثناء اليوم ..
the Nutmeg collects energy
"ذا نت ميج " تستقطب الطاقة
from solar panels on the roof of the wheelhouse,
بواسطة اشعة الشمس عبر ألواح موضوعة على سطح منزلي
and from a 450 watt turbine
ومن توربين استطاعته 450 وات
up the mast.
مرفوع الى صاري
So that when it gets dark,
وعندما يأتي الظلام
I've got plenty of power.
يكون لدي كم كاف من الطاقة
And I can light up the Nutmeg like a beacon.
يكفي لكي انير " ذا نت ميج " تماما
And so I go in there until the early hours of the morning,
لذا اذهب دوما الى هناك واقضي الليل بطوله حتى ساعات الصباح الاولى
and I work on new songs.
واعمل على الاغاني الجديدة
I'd like to play to you guys,
واريد ان اعزف لكم يا اصدقاء
if you're willing to be the first audience to hear it.
وسوف تكونون اول من يسمع هذه الاغنية
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
It's about Billie Holiday.
انها عن عطلة " بيلي "
And it appears that,
وبدأت قصتها
some night in 1947
في ليلة من عام 1947
she left her physical space
حيث تركت - بيلي - يومها جسدها
and was missing all night,
واختفت طيلة الليل
until she reappeared in the morning.
ومن ثم عادت اليه في الصباح
But I know where she was.
وكنت اعلم الى اين ذهبت
She was with me on my lifeboat.
لقد كانت في قارب النجاة الخاص بي
And she was hot.
وقد كانت مثيرة جدا
(Music)
(موسيقى)
♫ Billie crept softly ♫
♫تسللت بهدوء - بيلي -♫
♫ into my waking arms ♫
♫الى يدي المنيرتين ♫
♫ warm like a sip of sour mash ♫
♫الدافئتين كحزمة من نور الشمس♫
♫ Strange fruit for ♫
♫غريبة .. مخلصة ♫
♫ a sweet hunk of trash ♫
♫تحوي بعض المشاكل .. ولكنها جميلة ♫
♫ Panic at the stage door ♫
♫وقد ذعرت على بوابة ♫
♫ of Carnegie Hall ♫
♫قاعة كارنيج ♫
♫ "Famous Jazz Singer Gone AWOL" ♫
♫عازف الجاز الشهير ♫
♫ Must have left the building ♫
♫والذي رفع المبنى بعزف ♫
♫ body and soul ♫
♫بجسده وبروحه ♫
♫ On a creaky ♫
♫على البيانو ♫
♫ piano stool tonight ♫
♫المهتز في الليل ♫
♫ as the moon is my ♫
♫لان القمر ♫
♫ only witness ♫
♫هو شاهدي الوحيد ♫
♫ She was breathing ♫
♫لقد كانت تتنفس ♫
♫ in my ear ♫
♫في اذني ♫
♫ "This time it's love" ♫
♫هذا الوقت هو وقت الحب ♫
♫ But love is a loaded pistol ♫
♫ولكن الحب ما هو الا مسدس محشو ♫
♫ By daybreak she's gone ♫
♫وعندما جاء الصباح ذهبت ♫
♫ Over the frozen river, home ♫
♫عبر النهر المتجمد .. الى المنزل ♫
♫ Me and Johnny Walker ♫
♫انا وجوني والكر ♫
♫ See in the new age ♫
♫راينا العصر الجديد♫
♫ alone ♫
♫وحدنا ♫
♫ Stay with me ♫
♫ابقي معي ♫
♫ again tonight ♫
♫مرة اخرى الليلة ♫
♫ Billie, time, ♫
♫بيلي - الزمن ♫
♫ time is a wily trickster ♫
♫الزمن مخادع ماكر ♫
♫ Still an echo ♫
♫ومازال الصدى ♫
♫ in my heart says, ♫
♫في قلبي يقول ♫
♫ "This time it's love" ♫
♫هذا وقت الحب ♫
(Applause)
(تصفيق)